If war is Hell, then what comes after?
The Good German is a drama, mystery, romance film directed by Steven Soderbergh.
An American journalist arrives in Berlin just after the end of World War Two.
He becomes involved in a murder mystery surrounding a dead GI who washes up at a
lakeside mansion during the Potsdam negotiations between the Allied powers.
Soon his investigation connects with his search for
his married pre-war German lover.
Jake Geismar, played by George Clooney.
Lena Brandt, played by Cate Blanchett.
Tully, played by Tobey Maguire.
Colonel Muller, played by Beau Bridges.
Danny, played by Tony Curran.
Bernie Teitel, played by Leland Orser.
The Good German is a 2006 American neo-noir crime film.
A film adaptation of Joseph Kanon's  2001 novel, it was directed by Steven
Soderbergh, and stars George Clooney, Cate Blanchett, and Tobey Maguire.
Set in Berlin following the Allied victory over the Nazis, it begins as a murder mystery but weaves in
elements involving the American postwar employment of Nazi rocket scientists in Operation Paperclip.
The film was shot in black-and-white and is designed to imitate the appearance of film noir from the 1940s, although it also
includes material – such as sex scenes and swearing – that would have been prohibited by the Production Code.
Its poster is a homage to the poster for Casablanca (1942, also from
Warner Bros.), as is the closing scene at an airport.
Besides being shot in black-and-white, the film was also shot in the traditional 1.37:1
aspect ratio (known as the Academy ratio), which declined in use from about 1953.
The DVD release keeps the original aspect ratio, though the theatrical release, and other
DVD Releases, used the slightly more modern but still unusual 1.66:1 ratio.
The film received mixed reviews and grossed $6 million
worldwide against a budget of $32 million.
It was nominated for the Berlin International Film Festival Golden
Bear and the Academy Award for Best Original Score.
The film explores themes of berlin, germany, chauffeur,
corruption, love of one's life, nazi.
The tone is intense and emotional and mind_bending.